Return to the Source.
The Matrix Resurrections is a science fiction, action,
adventure film directed by Lana Wachowski.
Plagued by strange memories, Neo's life takes an unexpected turn
when he finds himself back inside the Matrix.
Neo / Thomas Anderson, played by Keanu Reeves.
Trinity / Tiffany, played by Carrie-Anne Moss.
Morpheus / Agent Smith, played by Yahya Abdul-Mateen II.
Smith, played by Jonathan Groff.
Bugs, played by Jessica Henwick.
The Analyst, played by Neil Patrick Harris.
The Matrix Resurrections is a 2021 American science fiction action film co-produced and directed by
Lana Wachowski, who co-wrote the screenplay with David Mitchell and Aleksandar Hemon.
It is the fourth in The Matrix film series.
The film stars an ensemble cast including Keanu Reeves, Carrie-Anne Moss, Yahya Abdul-Mateen II, Jessica Henwick, Jonathan Groff,
Neil Patrick Harris, Priyanka Chopra Jonas, Lambert Wilson, Christina Ricci, Freema Agyeman, and Jada Pinkett Smith.
Set sixty years after Revolutions, the film follows Neo, who lives a seemingly ordinary life as
a video game developer having trouble with distinguishing fantasy from reality.
A group of rebels, with the help of a programmed version of Morpheus, free Neo from a new
version of the Matrix and fight a new enemy that holds Trinity captive.
Following the release of Revolutions, the Wachowskis
denied the possibility of another Matrix film.
Warner Bros.
constantly expressed interest in reviving the franchise, hiring Zak Penn to write a new
screenplay after the Wachowskis refused every offer to create more sequels.
In late 2019, a fourth Matrix film was finally announced, with Lana Wachowski returning
as director without Lilly, and Reeves and Moss reprising their roles.
Filming started in February 2020, but was halted the
next month by the COVID-19 pandemic.
Wachowski considered abandoning the film, but was
encouraged by the cast to finish it.
Filming resumed in August and concluded three months later.
The Matrix Resurrections premiered at the Castro Theater in San Francisco on December 16, 2021,
and was released theatrically and via the HBO Max streaming service by Warner Bros.
Pictures on December 22.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, and underperformed at the box office,
grossing only $160.2 million worldwide against a $190 million production budget.
It received a nomination for Best Special Visual Effects
at the 75th British Academy Film Awards.
A sequel is currently in development, with Drew Goddard set to direct.
The film explores themes of future, man vs machine, underground
world, artificial intelligence (a.i.), computer.
The tone is thought_provoking.